We're going to look at ovulation, which is going to
happen, and what is very important here is that we see we have the fringe of the ovary.
You've already seen the precise anatomy of the pelvic area, you've already seen the precise anatomy
of the uterus,
then the ovaries, and behind that, you have what we call the broad ligaments,
the round ligaments, the lombo-ovarian ligaments, the sacral ligaments, etc., but these are actually all one and the same tissue.
What do I mean by that? It is that if you observe embryology, the anatomy
of the uterus, you can see that it is a fold of the posterior parietal peritoneum.
You have the posterior parietal peritoneum, and during development, there will be a
posterior concentration to form a uterus and
to form...
the tubes, which will be located here. And what we observe is that in fact it
needs to be
mobile, because they must capture, you see, the oocyte,
with my sacrum, there is a movement,
as you can see, in a figure-eight shape, which
is linked to both growth mobility,
provided by movement and organized by motility.
Are you following me?
So I have this movement in the shape of a figure-eight,
but linked to a whole mesothelial tissue that is continuous
with the endopelvic fascia, etc.
Let's say now, if I look here at the level of my
digestive system,
I have my Toldt's fascia.
which is here, and it inserts to the posterior parietal peritoneum.
Well, if I have appendicitis, for example, and I have
a stop or a loss on one plane
of energy, on a fascial plane of this continuity, it can disturb
the motility or the mobility
of my ovary to capture the oocyte.
The peritoneum must be free to allow this
fertilization.
To enable this fertilization, to first capture the fringe.
If it doesn’t capture it, the oocyte remains in the
pelvic area, let's say,
this can lead to what we call extra-tubal fertilizations.
which are more of a danger.
Why? Because if we observe and see the anatomy,
there is a direct link from the vagina to the peritoneal cavity
through this continuity, you see.
In men, it is closed because of the Müllerian tubercle
and the Wolffian duct differentiating, so there is no connection.
It has created first here, for the isolation of spermatozoa.
A major barrier, very important, which we call a sort of
vaginal acidity.
A hygiene present in women, which is very important to destroy any
unnecessary bacteria.
First thing.
Then, there will be a second thing.
There will be here a small mucous plug at the level of the
cervix
of the uterus.
You have the cervix of the uterus.
Here, you see a little mucous plug.
If we look from the front, we find that this mucous plug,
once a month, allows small openings
laterally.
The spermatozoa can pass through.
If it doesn't work, they will close.
There are secretions.
It needs to close most of the time.
If there is really an increase, there can be scenarios of loss.
which are discharges related among other things to that.
So this opening here is necessary.
Then, I will go into the uterus,
and I will enter the uterus,
and very quickly, what will happen?
There will be, and this is something that is very present in the body,
and we will talk later about asymmetry processes,
is that at the level of these cervices here, we do not see them.
Well, in fact, there are tiny cilia.
So not only do we arrive
we have already been shot
and if we pass
we have to get through the cervix
at the right moment we can go
then we arrive in the uterus
and there we still need to take the correct direction
generally, we are attracted by warmth
by sugar, by electrical activity
we move towards the region
and there
it is cleaned
but all of this is very important
why?
because it will not
that is, there is a spermatozoon that wins.
It is not just one that wins.
It is a group that allows us to achieve one thing.
That's why nature is well made.
There is no single winner.
Naturally, it's still the one who is the straightest,
a bit sturdier, you see, to make it.
Because it has to pass through all these barriers.
Because some have traits in their spermatozoa.
Some have their flagella tangled, so what do they do? They turn in circles.
At the moment I arrive here, I will encounter yet another important phase,
is that I must reach the most optimal zone,
meaning where the quality of the thermal balance is the best
and where the oocyte is really ready to welcome the spermatozoon.
Because on the membrane, there are what we call...
proteins, called
glycoproteins.
This is called ZP3.
ZP3 is a
It is a recognition
that occurs first at the level
of the membrane.
Once we have recognized each other,
would you mind opening, I can enter.
But if you don't have this recognition,
it is not possible.
This means that our first recognition
is a membranous recognition.
Am I recognized?
But look now what happens.
Most of the time, we are now doing in vitro fertilizations.
In vitro fertilizations, there are different types,
but the one that is most common now is what we call fixi.
That is to say we take, I come with a large needle,
I don’t care about your back part, I go inside
and I drop the spermatozoon
and the genetic material of the spermatozoon.
This means that there is no recognition.
We don’t yet have much, much, much hindsight, but one of the risks is that we provoke
increasingly fertility problems.
You see?
But these children also come for consultation.
My first question is
how did the conception happen?
Was it a natural conception or not?
Very rarely
will they tell you in the first place.
They come with their baby
one here, one there, we ask
were there any miscarriages?
It's important.
There are uteruses where frankly
there are many miscarriages, they need to be cleaned.
The uteri energetically, mentally
energetically, must be released, it doesn't work, and if
it's not possible, the only thing
we can do is recognize the child, I recognize it through my
membrane, through the
mother, I make a contact, there are mothers who do not touch the heart, they do not touch
the belly, they have not touched, they have not recognized, they have not been
led to do so, we must reconnect them to that, you see, we need to reconnect them between the heart
and the mother and the belly, so I restore that knowledge.
They are morally, if you will,
but it is important, and children,
they see that, they feel that.
What is very important is that we must
know our history.
The worst, the worst,
for an individual, is what we call
the unsaid.
But the most important,
is the idea that I must
know my story.
It’s a wonderful gift,
it can be something magnificent.
Close to me,
there's a story like this about a woman
who went through a donation
of spermatozoa
and the child does not know
he does not know his story
so he carries within him
a lie
he does not know
because tissues cannot lie
they cannot hide from you
you cannot hide in tissues
you can hide it in your mind
but not in your tissues
that's why
not reach a power in your hands because we touch something that
The oocyte, it is polarized, and I told you, at the moment the spermatozoon arrives,
there’s a reorganization of these axes, creating dorsal
ventral apical-cranial-caudal axes.
It's as if, but you shouldn’t see it too strongly, but it’s as if, in humans,
this moment is a connection with the heart.
the symbolic heart.
And so, what would I do?
I touch the heart.
But not in its soul.
Because the true center is there.
With awareness, you know.
I say, I understood you, Lourdes.
I try.
If you come to my place and I know this,
I cannot not do it
the ovary
the oocyte that is going to come out
you will understand
and then here the fringe
that comes
to capture this huge potential of life
look at an ovulation
it's not
It's not tiny.
It's not just a little cell, guys.
No, let's keep quiet.
And there, we see, look here, appearing, you see, right here.
With our little nourishing cells, all this liquid.
We see the spermatozoon arriving.
We can see the environment.
and they move through the tiny cilia.
And there, they arrive and will first attempt to pass through this layer,
there are still several, to reach the zona pellucida,
to finally reach the membrane,
and there again, they must have this membrane recognition.
And there, some are looking for the key.
and he is the one
who has the key
and what does he do once he has the key?
there is a transformation
you see of this tissue
he will release an acid
it's really an attack
to enter the mucous membrane
it's a
something quite strong to enter
an acrosomal acid
and he will enter, he will lose his tail
and at that moment
there’s closure, through degranulation around the membrane
to close off to everyone.
Here we see the two genetic materials that will
meet. It will form here
the encounter. This is really an important image we see here. We
see the meeting
of these two genetic materials. Look what happens, how incredible.
we see that it is alive
and now look, all of a sudden
I think we will see it here
there, you see, look closely, you can see well
hop
and now, the second important photo
it's already a big cell
and now we enter a process
dynamic that will interest us
and this first cell of life
will form the first two cells of your life, what we call the
two first blastocysts, the two first blastomeres.
This means the first two germ mother cells.
They are there.
Because for me, it all started, this whole work in embryology, I
was in search of this polarity, these things.
And there.
I arrive with this to a biologist friend.
I found the image of the axis, etc.
Because I had seen that there were polar bodies
and that it looked like that.
And I saw an axis.
Well, I went to a biologist friend
who taught me a lot,
Marc Ruffray, an osteopath biologist.
A sort of living library.
There are those kinds.
They have read more books than you will read in three lifetimes.
And on this,
the idea is amazing
but even if it exists
it’s already something before
and it is what we have done
we ultimately started in my research
until searching in the oocyte
for these first phases of polarity
with these flags
to form
a possible pre-programming
of the system.